Guide to the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- OVERSIZE
  - Grayson, Harry, and Maurice Rapkin: manuscript book, "Engineer Pete and his Foolish Questions," with ink illustrations (in Series I), undated (Box 43, Folder 627)
  - Gruelle, Johnny: drawings (2) of Raggedy Ann and Andy; gouache, ink, colored pencil, and collage on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1920 (Box 43, Folder 628-629)
  - Lenski, Lois: drawing for cover of Songs of Mr. Small; ink and watercolor on paper (in Series I), 1954 (Box 44, Folder 630)
  - Merrill, Frank T.: drawing, "A Merry Christmas"; ink, pencil, and Chinese white on paper mounted on mat board (in Series I), undated (Box 44, Folder 631)
  - Mora, Jo: drawings (8) for Reynard the Fox; brown monochrome watercolor on paper (in Series I), 1901 (Box 44, Folder 632-639)
  - Mora, Jo: drawings (8) for Reynard the Fox; brown ink and wash on paper (in Series I), 1901 (Box 45, Folder 640-647)
  - Newell, Peter: drawing, "The shrapnel bursting o'er his head's the climax of his troubles"; watercolor and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), undated (Box 46, Folder 648)
  - Pitz, Henry C.: drawings (3) for Robinson Crusoe, by Daniel Defoe; ink on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1936 (Box 46, Folder 649)
  - Plumer, William: broadside, "The Writing Master's Invitation and Instruction," Center School; holograph (in Series II), 1802 May 10 (Box 46, Folder 650)
  - Sarg, Tony: drawing, "Faust," for The Classics in Slang, by H. C. Witwer; ink, watercolor, and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1926 (Box 46, Folder 651)
  - Shinn, Everett: drawings (5) for The Night Before Christmas, by Clement Clarke Moore; ink, watercolor, and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1942 (Box 46, Folder 652-656)
  - Young, Art: drawing for "Long Ago," by Eugene Field; ink on paper (in Series I), 1897 (Box 46, Folder 657)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawing for Barnaby Rudge, by Charles Dickens; pencil and white chalk on paper (in Series I), undated (Box 47, Folder 658)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawing, possibly for James Fenimore Cooper novel; ink and wash on illustration board (in Series I), 1878 (Box 47, Folder 659)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr: drawing, figure sketches for unidentified project; pencil on illustration board (in Series I), undated (Box 47, Folder 660)
  - Daugherty, James Henry: drawing, "Democracy"; ink and opaque white on paper (in Series I), 1944 (Box 47, Folder 661)
  - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace): drawing for dust jacket for Father Goose: His Book, by L. Frank Baum; ink and black chalk on paper (in Series I), 1899 (Box 47, Folder 662)
  - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace): drawing for alternate title page for The Songs of Father Goose, by L. Frank Baum and Alberta N. Hall; ink and pencil on paper (in Series I), 1900 (Box 47, Folder 663)
  - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace): drawing for end papers for Denslow's Mother Goose; ink and pencil on paper (in Series I), 1901 (Box 47, Folder 664)
  - Johnson & Warner: indentures (2), partnership agreement and dissolution of partnership of Jacob Johnson and Benjamin Warner, Philadelphia; holograph (in Series II), 1808, 1816 (Box 47, Folder 665)
  - Lewis, Earl B.: drawing for Little Cliff's First Day of School, by Clifton L. Taulbert; watercolor and pencil on paper (in Series I), 2001 (Box 47, Folder 666)
  - Neill, John R.: drawing, "Tik-Tok of Oz," for Tik-Tok of Oz, by L. Frank Baum; ink and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), 1914 (Box 47, Folder 667)
  - Provenson, Alice and Martin: drawing, cover design for A Peaceable Kingdom: The Shaker Abecedarius; watercolor, ink, and pencil on paper (in Series I), circa 1981 (Box 47, Folder 668)
  - Shinn, Everett: drawing for The Night Before Christmas, by Clement Clarke Moore; ink, watercolor, and charcoal on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1942 (Box 48, Folder 669)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Angell, Clare: drawing for Lost at Sea, by Horatio Alger, Jr.; ink and gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1904 (Box 48, Folder 670)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Bridge, W. B.: drawing for When Santiago Fell, by Ralph Bonehill; ink and gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1914 (Box 48, Folder 671)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Nuttall, Charles: drawing, "The circus," for The Bobbsey Twins in the Country, by Laura Lee Hope; gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1903 (Box 48, Folder 672)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Rogers, Walter S.: drawings (2) for The Rover Boys Down East, by Arthur M. Winfield; ink and gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1911 (Box 48, Folder 673)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Shute, A. B.: drawing, "'You shall go on board,' said Dan Baxter," for The Rover Boys on the River, by Arthur M. Winfield; gouache and pencil on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1905 (Box 48, Folder 674)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Shute, A. B.: drawings (2) for The Young Book Agent, by Horatio Alger, Jr.; gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1905 (Box 48, Folder 675)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/Shute, A. B.: drawings (2) for The Young Volcano Explorers, by Edward Stratemeyer; gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1902 (Box 48, Folder 676)
  - Stratemeyer Syndicate/unidentified artist: drawings (3) for With Boone on the Frontier, or, The Pioneer Boys of Old Kentucky, by Ralph Bonehill; ink and gouache on illustration board (in Series I), circa 1903 (Box 48, Folder 677)
  - Vergoose, Isaac: indenture for division of estate, signed by Vergoose's four children, Peter, Isaac, Anna, and Elizabeth, and Elizabeth's husband, the printer Thomas Fleet (in Series II), 1734 Feb 21 (Box 48, Folder 678)
  - Unidentified: drawing for cover of Spencer's New Copy Books; ink, wash, and pencil on paperboard (in Series II), 1884 (Box 48, Folder 679)
- BROADSIDE
  - Burchfield, Charles: drawing, "The Counter-pane Fairy," after Katherine Pyle; gouache on paper (in Series I), 1913 (Box Bsd, folder 680)
  - Kollner, Augustus: drawing of two female nudes; ink on paper (in Series I), undated (Box Bsd, folder 681)
  - Shinn, Everett: drawing for The Night Before Christmas, by Clement Clarke Moore; watercolor on paper (in Series I), circa 1942 (Box Bsd, folder 682)
- ART STORAGE
  - Cady, Harrison, "The Artist in his Studio"; oil on Masonite, framed (in Series I), undated (Box Art, Folder 683)
  - Gramatky, Hardie: drawing, "Little Toot"; pastel on paper, framed (in Series I), undated (Box Art, Folder 684)
  - Keller, Arthur Ignatius: drawing, "'I promise to make your little girl happy,' he whispered," for The Virginian, by Owen Wister; gouache on illustration board, framed (in Series I), 1902 (Box Art, Folder 685)
  - Pogány, Willy: drawing, "The Emperor holds a stick..." for Gulliver's Travels, by Jonathan Swift; watercolor on paper, framed (in Series I), circa 1917 (Box Art, Folder 686)
  - Shepard, Ernest H.: drawings (2) for The Wind in the Willows, by Kenneth Grahame; ink, pencil, and watercolor on paper, framed (in Series I), circa 1960 (Box Art, Folder 687)
  - Smith, Jessie Willcox: painting, "On the top of the great beech-tree," for At the Back of the North Wind, by George MacDonald; oil on artist's board, framed (in Series I), circa 1919 (Box Art, Folder 688)
  - Unidentified artist: assemblage, with valentine and paper inscribed "Nancy Hawk"; watercolor and collage on paper, framed (in Series II), 1838, undated (Box Art, Folder 689)
- RESTRICTED FRAGILE MATERIALS
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 9, folder 178 (Box 49, Folder 690)
  - Box 9, folder 189 (Box 49, Folder 691)
  - Box 9, folder 192 (Box 49, Folder 692)
  - Box 10, folder 202 (Box 49, Folder 693)
  - Box 10, folder 228 (Box 49, Folder 694)
  - Box 15, folder 316 (Box 49, Folder 695)
  - Box 33, folder 529 (Box 49, Folder 696)
  - Box 9, folders 169-170 (Box 50, Folder 697)
- DECORATED BOXES
  - Boxes for Andre, Bemelmens, Burgess, Chapman, Clemens Dodgson, Franklin, Habberton, Hancock, Key, Lincoln, Sendak, Wiese, and Metamorphosis (Box 51)
  - Boxes for Baum, Cox, Lathrop, Valenti, Whiting, and Wiese (Box 52)
  - Boxes for Anglund, Burgess, Cady, Cox, Field, Ives, Smith (Box 53)